# **NICK NEWBURG**

# **WEB DEVELOPER**

# Summary

Logical problem solver that adores programming rewarding creative solutions. I love competitive card/board games, fishing, hockey and anything philosophical. I have worked and volunteered for <u>AssistList.ca</u> for 8 months in a full product cycle environment. Using professional version control with feature branches and test environments hosted. Over a dozen features or projects launched in coordination with the design or marketing team. My experience enables me to assimilate into a development role smoothly as I have evolved my education into real world development phenomenally. A more detailed summary can be found on my website nicknewburg.ca

# **Employment**

## AssistList - Canada summer jobs

Full Stack Web Developer

Jul. 2020 - Aug. 2020

Worked with <u>AssistList.ca</u> in a full product cycle environment with multiple feature and test branches simultaneously deployed. Worked within a sprint cycle management structure with a designer and developer in a team to launch 5 projects under strategic timelines.

Acted as liaison between design and development team discussing time/cost benefit of features in question demonstrating innate ability to communicate between teams. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React Redux, Ruby on Rails, Docker, Semantic UI, PostgreSQL all used with advanced components and practices invoked. Including evolving previously built features and brand new features. Provided groundwork for a Design System outside the scope of the summer jobs objective.

#### **Sol Sunbelt Cookery**

Chef

Aug. 2012 - Apr. 2013

Worked as Garde manger/dishwasher in a high end restaurant. Preparing complex and intricate cold appetizers and salads. Simultaneously prepping for the entire kitchen while maintaining the dish area. Multitasking with a heavy sense of urgency was required on even the slowest shifts. During peak times it was a hurricane of frenzied activity.

## Cactus Club Cafe

Chef

Jun. 2011 - Jan. 2012

Multi tasked between the dish-pit, preparation area, and the appetizer station. There was always a task to be done and efficiency and growth was a constant every shift. Sequenced the order of jobs to maximize productivity at an ever improving rate.

# **Volunteering**

## **AssistList** · Development Manager

Mar. 2020 - Current

Working as a Web Developer with <u>AssistList.ca</u> in a React and Ruby on Rails environment hosted by AWS. Have created or modified dozens of features, both on the front end and back end. Strong Git version control experience working in a team with several developers, feature branches, and live test environments. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, React Redux, Ruby on Rails, Docker, Semantic UI, PostgreSQL all used with advanced components and practices involved. Continuously growing and expanding my ability to handle any challenge.

Manage orientation, recruitment, and cross team communication as development manager. Involved with other team leads to discuss procedural improvements, cross team projects like Google Analytics for marketing team or continuing development of a Design System library with the design team.

## Gordon Neighbourhood House · Tax Filer

Mar. 2016 - Apr. 2016

Filed personal income taxes for the elderly and disabled using Efile. Explained and chatted with those unable to understand or file their personal income tax returns.

## Contact

☑nicknewburg@gmail.com

O nicknewburg.ca

**\** 778-384-4459

**in** nicknewburg/

nnewburg n

## **Education**

Web Development Bootcamp

A full-time immersive web development course.

LANGARA COLLEGE Sep. 2013 - Sep. 2017
Business - Accounting/Computer Science
Studied and achieved 30 courses of general
business with a specification in accounting
and computer science.

## Skills

#### LANGUAGES & FRAMEWORKS

HTML - Advanced

CSS - Advanced

JavaScript - Advanced

React - Advanced

React Redux - Advanced

Ruby - Intermediate

Java - Intermediate

C++ - Intermediate

Node.js - Advanced

jQuery - Intermediate

EJS - Intermediate

Rails - Intermediate

Express.js - Intermediate

## **VERSION CONTROL / DATABASES**

Git - Advanced

Bit Bucket - Advanced

GitHub - Advanced

MongoDB - Beginner

PostgreSQL - Intermediate

Active Record - Beginner

#### **USER INTERFACE / DEV OPS / MISC**

Bootstrap - Advanced

Semantic UI - Advanced

Google Analytics - Beginner

Docker - Intermediate

AWS - Beginner

Digital Ocean - Beginner

Virtual Box - Intermediate

# **NICK NEWBURG**

# **WEB DEVELOPER**

# **Projects**

<u>Partners - AssistList</u> Aug. 2020

Single page project with advanced responsive design protocols, filtering back end data pulls, and allowing administrators to add, remove, or edit a partners name, description, or website link. Strong communication skills to collaborate with a design team over limitations of wire frames in question. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React Redux, Ruby on Rails, Semantic UI.

Resources - AssistList Aug. 2020

Multi page project involving a landing page, impressive responsive design, and implementing google maps. Strong end points written to pull from database and allow administrators to add, remove, or edit dynamic content without developers attention. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React Redux, Semantic UI, and Ruby on Rails, Google Maps, Iframe, and webkit hover transformations.

About Us - AssistList Jul. 2020

Multi page project with several strong responsive design elements at work. Numerous back end calls to present statistics and team members dynamically, allowing administrators to add, remove, or edit data without developer attention. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React Redux, Ruby on Rails, Semantic UI, and Slick-slider.

Portfolio Jan. 2020

A deployed website featuring a biography and live demos of projects compiled into one website. Using JS.Express, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Node.JS, PSQL, Ajax, Bootstrap, and Knex.

<u>PizzaShack</u> Sep. 2019 - Oct. 2019

PizzaShack is a full stack web application that emulates a food ordering service. Using JS.Express, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Node.JS, PSQL, Ajax, Bootstrap, and Knex.

Budgestory May 2019 - Jun. 2019

Budgestory is a full stack web app that allows users to manage their personal finances through interactive charts. It uses React, Express, PostgreSQL and a library called Highcharts.

BattleShip Apr. 2019

Battleship is a simple copy of the board game. It uses base technologies: HTML, CSS, and Jquery.

The Watering Hole May 2019

A full stack web application that used Express, HTML, CSS, Jquery, Ajax, Knex, Postgres, and Sessions. The application allowed used to post resources that had a description, URL, and picture for other users to view. Users could like, comment, and rate the resources.

Tweeter Apr. 2019

Tweeter is a single page application built with HTML, CSS, Node, Express and Jquery, Ajax, and MongoDB resembling a Twitter clone where users can post tweets and other users may view and like those tweets.

# **Activities**

#### Canucks Fan

I watched Roberto Luongo's first playoff game with my father leading to a quadruple overtime Victory for the Canucks lasting 138 minutes. Since then I have been an avid Canucks fan taking immense interest in the unpredictability and drama of sports for the first time in my life. Extremely active in stats and critical analysis of players.

## Magic the Gathering

Magic is a competitive card game that can be played in person or online. It is nearly 30 years old and offers players heavily analytical and strategic skill challenges for a game. Very communal and offers a platform for heavy discussion between deck creation, format health, and game strategy.

## **Dungeons and Dragons**

Combines the story telling of novels with the interaction and skill of a board game. Quite fun and very engaging, I love having a dwarf accent.

## **Fishing**

Not the greatest lover of the out doors but have found fishing to be extremely tranquil and relaxing. Often being hypnotized by the wake of the water. Find a very serene connection with our ancestral heritage long forgotten.